export const LEATHERWORKA2021 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Pick out a decorative design that produces dots from the options below.",
A: "Carving",
B: "Marbling",
C: "Stippling",
D: "Tooling",
answer: "C. Stippling",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The main objective for pounding leather is to make it",
A: "plastic",
B: "soft.",
C: "thin.",
D: "washable.",
answer: "B. soft",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Which of the following can be used to grease machine parts?",
A: "Paraffin wax",
B: "Shea butter",
C: "Lacquer",
D: "Thinner",
answer: "A. Paraffin wax",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Identify the odd term from the options below.",
A: "Adhesives",
B: "Grooves",
C: "Laces",
D: "Thongs",
answer: "D. Thongs",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Which of the following is a decoration on leather?",
A: "Buckle",
B: "D-ring",
C: "Scorching",
D: "Swivel",
answer: "C. Scorching",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. When a skin or hide is dried it beomes",
A: "flexible and workable.",
B: "fluffy and malleable.",
C: "hard and brittle.",
D: "stretchy and soft.",
answer: "C. hard and brittle",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The process of using alum and salt on skins to obtain white leather is known as",
A: "curing.",
B: "tanning.",
C: "tawing.",
D: "skiving.",
answer: "C. tawing",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Which of the following steps follow each other in succession in leather production?",
A: "Designing and sketching",
B: "Decorating and polishing",
C: "Finishing and trimming",
D: "Tracing and cutting",
answer: "D. Tracing and cutting",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Manual skiving is done with the knife",
A: "held in both hands.",
B: "placed under the leather.",
C: "pushed away from the cutter",
D: "pulled towards the cutter.",
answer: "D. pulled towards the cutter",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Threads for stitching are waxed primarily to",
A: "create a better slip.",
B: "give them a desired colour.",
C: "make them stronger.",
D: "obtain a better twist.",
answer: "A. create a better slip",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Temporary assembling of leather parts is done using",
A: "gum arabic.",
B: "rubber cement.",
C: "rivet.",
D: "thong.",
answer: "B. rubber cement",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. What is the use of methylated spirit in leatherwork? To",
A: "clean leather goods after production",
B: "cure skins and hides",
C: "make thick leather transparent",
D: "tan skins into leather",
answer: "A. clean leather goods after production",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Leather is shaved in order to",
A: "increase value.",
B: "increase thickness,",
C: "reduce cost.",
D: "reduce bulk.",
answer: "D. reduce bulk",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Prior to making slit stitches, the edges of the leather parts are",
A: "burnished.",
B: "skived,",
C: "punched.",
D: "smoothened.",
answer: "B. skived",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. In which of the following are elements and principles of design employed?",
A: "During the pre-tanning activities of leather production",
B: "Planning to establish leatherwork enterprise",
C: "During the process of leather production",
D: "Planning the production of an article",
answer: "D. Planning the production of an article",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. The tool used for tracing designs on leather is a",
A: "beveller.",
B: "modeller.",
C: "seeder.",
D: "shader.",
answer: "C. seeder",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Removing the hair and epidermis from skin to be made into leather is referred to as",
A: "dehairing.",
B: "fleshing.",
C: "graining.",
D: "staking.",
answer: "A. dehairing",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. The function of a leather talisman is",
A: "economic.",
B: "spiritual.",
C: "educational.",
D: "social.",
answer: "B. spiritual",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. What makes natural leather resistant to heat and decomposition?",
A: "Curing",
B: "Liming",
C: "Paring",
D: "Tanning",
answer: "D. Tanning",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Which of the following is normally sharpened with both emery cloth and file?",
A: "Chisel",
B: "Modeller",
C: "Skiving knife",
D: "Spring punch",
answer: "A. Chisel",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The skill of matching and constrasting colours is most needed when",
A: "dyeing leather.",
B: "weaving leather strips together.",
C: "doing appliqué work.",
D: "embossing patterns on leather.",
answer: "C. doing appliqué work",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Which of the following is a step in carving?",
A: "Casing the leather",
B: "Piercing the leather",
C: "Thonging the outline",
D: "Using a chisel",
answer: "D. Using a chisel",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Select the qualities of a butt from the following options\nI. hard\nII. soft\nIII. strong\nIV. thick",
A: "J and II only",
B: "II and III only",
C: "II, 111 and IV only",
D: "I, II and IV only",
answer: "C. II, III and IV only",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Exhibition of all kinds of products is referred to as",
A: "Bazaar",
B: "Gifex",
C: "Indutech",
D: "Panafest",
answer: "A. Bazaar",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The best reason for the leather worker to conduct a market survey is to check",
A: "how his leather product can be priced.",
B: "the number of people selling the same product.",
C: "whether to increase or reduce the price of the product.",
D: "whether the product will meet the taste of the target group.",
answer: "D. whether the product will meet the taste of the target group",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. In pricing a leather product, the last but one factor that is considered is the",
A: "cost of material.",
B: "labour cost.",
C: "profit margin.",
D: "total expenditure,",
answer: "C. profit margin",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Which of the following leathers is produced with vegetable tannin extracts?",
A: "Garment leather",
B: "Sole leather",
C: "Upper leather",
D: "Suede leather",
answer: "A. Garment leather",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Which group of people established the preservation of pelts by 2,500 BC?",
A: "Indians",
B: "Ghanaians",
C: "Greeks",
D: "Egyptians",
answer: "D. Egyptians",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The most appropriate tool for cutting curves on heavy leather is",
A: "safety skiver.",
B: "safety knife.",
C: "skiving knife.",
D: "stanley knife.",
answer: "B. safety knife",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Why did the early man store water in a skin bag?",
A: "It was the most available container",
B: "He had a nice taste of water",
C: "The water was free from impurities",
D: "He increased his travelling range",
answer: "D. He increased his travelling range",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Templates as cutting aid can also be used as a means of",
A: "checking the suitability of the design.",
B: "making the leather flat before using it.",
C: "checking the thickness of the leather.",
D: "helping to stretch leather to remove all dirt before using it.",
answer: "A. checking the suitability of the design",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Identify the leather which is ideal for tooling from the options below.",
A: "Morocco",
B: "Peccary",
C: "Suede",
D: "Nappa",
answer: "A. Morocco",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Toggling is a method that involves",
A: "flaying the raw skin,",
B: "oiling the raw hide.",
C: "pounding the hide.",
D: "stretching the hide.",
answer: "D. stretching the hide",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. To test for chrome-tanned leather",
A: "cut a cross section.",
B: "crumple the leather.",
C: "drop some spirit on it.",
D: "soak it in water.",
answer: "D. soak it in water",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. A person who uses treated hides and skins to make footwears is called",
A: "cobbler.",
B: "leather worker.",
C: "shoemaker.",
D: "upholsterer.",
answer: "C. shoemaker",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Which of the following leathers is recommended for use in herringbone stitching?",
A: "Calf",
B: "Suede",
C: "Chamois",
D: "Skiver",
answer: "A. Calf",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Applying heat and pressure on leather to obtain a raised image is called",
A: "buffing.",
B: "embossing.",
C: "graining.",
D: "glazing.",
answer: "B. embossing",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Dyes are said to be fast if they",
A: "make the leather shine.",
B: "are very expensive.",
C: "have many uses.",
D: "do not fade easily.",
answer: "D. do not fade easily",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. The leather articles that early man used were",
A: "puppets and drums.",
B: "drums and slings.",
C: "puppets and vellum.",
D: "slings and vellum.",
answer: "B. drums and slings",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. In early coaches, leather took the place of",
A: "axles.",
B: "tyres.",
C: "springs.",
D: "wheels,",
answer: "D. He increased his travelling range",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},


]